原视频名：Why SpaceX Will Move To New Thrusters To Simplify Starship
原作者名：Scott Manley
视频来源：youtu.be/vKiHCaA7hCY
原视频发布日期：20210712
字幕翻译：旋火
Hello, it's Scott Manley here.
你好 我是Scott Manley
Down in Boca Chica Texas, SpaceX is continuing to work on the BFR.
在德克萨斯州的博卡奇卡 SpaceX正在继续进行BFR的工作
他们把名字改成了超重助推器
但仍是一枚超级TMD大的火箭(BFR)
And finally, they're getting around to testing a booster,
最后 他们正着手测试一枚助推器
so there hasn't been much Starship activity in the last month,
所以上个月没有太多的星船(二级)的活动
because it's all about boosters all the time.
因为最近的新闻一直都是关于助推器的
There is a booster on the test stand.
在测试台上有一枚助推器
We think it already did a pressure test.
我们认为它已经做了一次压力测试
and now it's getting engines installed that it can do a proper cryogenic proof test
而现在它正在安装发动机 以便能够进行适当的低温验证测试
and potentially test fire with a large number of engines.
并有可能用大量的发动机进行试车
Now this booster, we don't think it's actually going to fly.
现在这枚助推器 我们不认为它真的会飞
There's another one that's going to go for that.
还有另一枚会进行试飞
And we know what the flight plan is
而且我们知道飞行计划是什么
because they had to make FCC filings for the communication requirements.
因为他们必须为通信需求进行FCC备案
And this included the trajectory.
而这包括飞行轨迹
The combined booster and Starship is designed to launch out at Boca Chica,
计划上 助推器和星船组合体会从博卡奇卡发射出去
head out east across the Gulf of Mexico.
向东穿过墨西哥湾
After stage separation, the booster will perform a flip boost back, but it will then land offshore.
在级间分离后 助推器将进行翻转和返程点火 但随后将在海上降落
Probably won't land on a landing pad because those aren't ready yet.
可能不会降落在一个着陆场上 因为那些着陆场还没有准备好
Starship will then continue down range and thread its way through the Caribbean islands,
然后 星船将继续按计划飞行 并在加勒比海岛屿上空穿行
The trajectory very carefully carries it to avoid as much land as possible.
轨迹会非常小心地 尽可能地避开陆地
After that, heads across the Atlantic, across Africa, Indian Ocean, Indonesia
之后 穿越大西洋 穿过非洲 印度洋 印度尼西亚
and then into Pacific north of Hawaii, where it will perform
然后进入夏威夷以北的太平洋 在那里它将进行
The Starship will perform an aerodynamic descent and landing in the ocean.
空气动力学下降并在海洋中降落
And again, landing in the ocean, about sixty miles north of Hawaii
再一次 在海洋中降落 在夏威夷以北约96.6km处
and I'm not sure if that's going to be recovered or not.
而我不确定这是否会被回收
But we know that they're not going to land these on barges,
但我们知道 他们不会将这些东西降落在驳船上
because first of all, Phobos and Deimos, the two large platforms are still in docks, getting modified.
因为首先 福波斯和得摩斯这两个大型平台仍然在码头上在进行改造
And the existing ones
而现有的则是
Of Course I Still Love You and Just Read The Instructions, they're just too small.
当然我还爱你 (OCISLY)和只要读下说明书 (JRTI) 实在是太小了
like, Of Course I Still Love You, by the way, just got moved to the West Coast.
顺便说一下 OCISLY刚刚被转移到西海岸
It put on a barge called the Mighty Servant
它被放在一艘叫做强大的仆人 的驳船上
which carried it through the Panama Canal.
运送它通过巴拿马运河
And it's being offloaded right now in Long Beach
现正在长滩被卸下
to support a number of launches by SpaceX out of Vandenberg.
以支持SpaceX在范登堡的一些发射活动
There's a new one, though, which we just got saw some video off called A Shortfall Of Gravitas.
不过 我们刚刚看到了一段新无人船的视频 叫做重力的短暂缺失 (ASOG)
And there's a nice little drone shot of this.
而且是一段漂亮的无人机拍摄画面
This is basically the same frame.
这基本上是同一个画面
It's like a Marmac.
它差不多是Marmac系列的
I think the designation is Marmac 302.
我想它的名称是Marmac 302
So it's the same sort of underlying shasse as the other barges,
所以它和其他驳船的底层结构是一样的
bu the hardware seems to be vastly improved.
但设备似乎有很大的改进
This was shown at sea, making some speed,
海上展示的这段视频显示 其具有一定的速度
so it looks like they're no longer going to need the tugs
那么看起来他们不再需要拖船
to pull these out to the ocean for landing and bringing them back.
来把这些东西拉到海上 然后再把它们带回来
The will still need support ships,
他们仍然需要支援船
because you can't have the people on the barge during the landing,
因为在着陆过程中 你不可能让人在驳船上
but A Shortfall Of Gravitas looks a whole lot sleeker and high tech
但是 ASOG看起来更时尚 更高科技
and hey it's another name then, inspired by Iain Banks' Culture novels.
而且 嘿 这是另一个启发自伊恩·班克斯的文明 小说
But yeah, it is kind of weird that people are like,
但是 是的 这有点奇怪 人们都这么说
surely you're going to try and recover these very expensive test articles
你肯定会尝试回收这些非常昂贵的测试物体
and of course that's something that didn't make sense.
但 当然 这并不合理
Previous to SpaceX everyone was dumping their boosters in the ocean or on land.
在SpaceX之前 每个人都会把他们的助推器扔到海洋或陆地上
But now that SpaceX is doing it
但现在 SpaceX正这样做
people are now horrified that they'll be dropping their boosters into the ocean again for testing,
人们现在惊恐地发现 他们会再次把他们的助推器丢入海里以进行测试
and that's what they did with the Falcon 9.
而这就是他们对猎鹰9号的做法
They would land it in the ocean to show that they could actually land it.
他们会把它降落在海里 以验证降落是可行的
And only after a few failed barge attempts did they actually get to perform a return-to-the-launch-site.
而只有在几次失败的驳船尝试之后 才真正能进行返回发射场的机动
And then they stuck the landing for the first time,
然后他们第一次成功着陆
Anyway look, SpaceX are pushing hard for this flight.
无论如何 看 SpaceX正在努力推动这次飞行
At one point, and I think they're still saying this,
某次 我认为他们仍在说
they're saying the intended flight date is July,
预定的飞行日期在7月
which I don't believe, for a second.
我一点也不信
It's Elon time.
这是马一龙时间
But at least one of the regulatory filings to put a Starlink antenna on Starship itself.
但至少有一份监管文件是把星链天线放在星船本身上
I think that has a start date of August 1st.
我记得开始日期是8月1日
And yeah obviously, that's not going to make a July launch.
是的 显然 这不可能在7月发射
I think if they make it before the end of the year,
我认为 如果他们在年底前完成
that will still be incredibly impressive
那将仍然是令人难以置信的
given the size of this thing will probably be SLS to an orbital launch,
考虑到这个东西的大小 可能相当于SLS(从研发)到轨道的发射(的时间)
which is of course you can do asterisks and say, well, this isn't a full vehicle?
当然 你可以加上星号 说 这不是一个完整的航天器
But I actually don't want to talk about this booster test flight.
但实际上我不想谈论这枚助推器的试飞(过程)
There's been a lot of speculation about it.
关于它已经有很多猜测了
I want to talk about a piece of hardware which was sided on the booster.
我想谈谈助推器侧壁上安装的一个设备
This here is a photo by Brady Caniston.
这是由布雷迪·卡尼斯顿拍摄的照片
And what you can see is a whole mass of plumbing
你可以看到一大堆管道
and some what look like, thrust chambers and nozzles and of course a cute little face in there.
和一些看起来像推力室和喷嘴的东西 当然还有一张可爱的小脸在里面
I haven't quite figured out who that is.
我还不知道那张脸是谁
Everybody looked to this and said, oh, that's a hot gas, RCS thruster.
每个人都看着这个并说 哦 那是一个热气RCS推进器
And and so of course I took this picture, and I explained on Twitter
因此 当然我截取了这张照片 并在推特上(如此)解释了
why SpaceX want to move over to hot gas RCS
为什么SpaceX想转向热气RCS
because it's more powerful and because it will use the same propellants as the main engines.
因为它更强大 因为它将使用与主发动机相同的推进剂
And pretty much in the next few hours,
而在接下来的几个小时里 几乎是这样
some guy called Elon Musk got into my Twitter mentions and said,
一个叫埃隆·马斯克的热心网友 在我的推特评论区写道
oh yes this is all very cool, but they're not gonna actually fly on the first orbital test flight,
哦 是的 这一切都非常酷 但他们不会在第一次轨道试飞中真正使用它
because they're basically trying to get this thing working,
因为基本上是他们正尝试让其工作
and cold gas RCS is where they are.
而冷气RCS是随时可以用的
They've tested these RCS pods already,
他们已经测试了这些RCS模块
We can hear them testing at McGregor,
我们可以听到他们在麦格雷戈的测试
well, like we don't see them testing because nobody flies drones over and around, I think.
好吧 我觉得之所以没有看到他们的测试 是因为没有人在上面和周围飞无人机
But you can hear these things being tested
但你可以听到这些东西正在测试
because they don't sound like a regular rocket engine.
因为它们的声音不像是普通的火箭发动机
The thing about RCS thrusters is they need to be real to provide like thrust inputs very quickly.
RCS推进器需要提供能真正地快速响应输入的推力
Think about you're playing Mario,
想想你在玩马里奥
and you're pushing the buttons in different directions very quickly.
而你正在非常迅速地按下不同方向的按键
Just imagine every time you push up, you have a rocket thrust of the fires.
试想一下 每次按键弹起来时 都有一台发动机在点火
So you can hear these things at McGregor if you are outside.
因此 如果你在麦格雷戈外面 是可以在听到这些东西的
So anyway, we know that these things are out there and and they exist,
那么无论如何 我们知道这些东西在那里
and you might want to know
而你可能想知道
what is the difference between the existing system and this new fancy hot gas.
现有系统和这种新的花哨的热气之间的区别是什么
So yes, existing system is called cold gas.
那么 是的 现有系统被称为冷气
That's where you have a high pressure cylinder of nitrogen.
也就是一罐高压的氮气瓶
You have a valve, and then you have a rocket nozzle.
上面带有一个阀门以及一个火箭喷嘴
And when you want that engine to fire, you open the valve
当你要点火发动机时 打开阀门
and the gas just goes through that nozzle and gives you thrust.
这样 气体就会通过喷嘴 带来推力
It gives you pretty low performance.
性能很低
The specific impulse is about 60 seconds.
比冲约为60秒
Hot gas thrusters is where you have a regular rocket engine,
(而)热气推进器类似于普通的火箭发动机
where you have either a monopropellant or a bipropellant.
可能使用单组元或者双组元推进剂
They mix and ignite in a combustion chamber, and you get thrust.
(对于双组元推进剂) 在一个燃烧室中混合并点燃 然后带来推力
In that case the thrust is much better,
在这种情况下 推力要好得多
the specific impulse is about 300 seconds at some high-end performance.
性能较高者 比冲可达300多秒
So yeah, that's 4 to 5 times better, which is much, much better.
那么 是的 那是前者的4到5倍 这要好得多
But the real advantage is for Starship, it will mean that
但对星船来说 真正的优势是
they are using the same propellent for their reaction control thrusters and their main thrusters.
他们的RCS推进器和主推进器会使用相同的推进剂
It means that they're not having to deal with nitrogen.
这意味着他们不需要处理氮气
And it means that
也就是说
they're also not having to deal with other typical propellants that are used in reaction control thrusters.
他们也不需要处理其他用于RCS推进器的典型推进剂
Most reaction control thrusters in space,
太空中的大多数RCS推进器
there are very small engines designed for basically rotating the vehicle and translating and everything.
有非常小的发动机 基本上是为旋转飞行器和平移之类的事情而设计的
These very small engines generally need to build fire quickly and stop quickly,
这些非常小的发动机通常需要快速地建立推力 并迅速停止
and they're usually pressure fed either mono propellent,
而且它们通常是挤压循环的单组元推进器
using hydrazine that gets decomposed with a catalysts,
比如在催化剂的作用下被分解的肼
sometimes they use peroxide, like the use of Soyuz
有时则使用过氧化物 如联盟飞船
or they use bipropellent hypergolics,
或者为双组元自燃推进剂
where you mix the propellants and they just explode instantly.
自燃推进剂在混合时就会立即爆炸
So those are usually monomethylhydrazine and nitrogen tetroxide,
那么自燃推进剂通常是单甲基肼和四氧化二氮
and that's what they use on the Dragon, for example, or the Space Shuttle.
例如 龙飞船或航天飞机
So those hypergolic propellants, they're very toxic,
那么自燃推进剂是非常有毒的
but also, they're completely different from the main propellants used to launch the rocket.
但同时 它们与用于发射火箭的主要推进剂完全不同
So if you can get a thruster which uses the same propellant
因此 如果推进器能使用相同的推进剂
that obviously simplifies a lot of your systems,
这显然简化了很多系统
and NASA actually tested this in flight on a vehicle called Morpheus.
而NASA实际上在一个叫墨菲斯的航天器的试飞中测试了这种RCS
Morpheus was a technology's testbed.
墨菲斯是一个技术测试平台
They wanted to do a whole bunch of interesting tech.
他们想做一大堆有趣的技术
They had a methane oxygen pressure fed engine as their main engine.
主发动机是挤压循环的液氧甲烷发动机
It had RCS thrusters which were cryogenic
RCS推进器使用低温推进剂
and this was one of the first vehicles to fly with cryogenic RCS thrusters.
而且这是第一批使用低温RCS推进器的航天器之一
They used methane and oxygen from the main tanks,
RCS使用主储罐内的甲烷和液氧
and they demonstrated that they could control vehicle.
验证了RCS可以控制航天器
It also had like cool auto navigation and landing, discovery and navigation.
它还有很酷的自动导航和着陆 发现和导航
It was great.
这很好
But that is somewhat different from what we have in Starship.
但这与星船中的情况有些不同
So in Morpheus, the main engine, was a pretty simple pressure fed engine,
那么对于墨菲斯 主发动机是一个相当简单的挤压循环发动机
and that meant the propellant tanks had to be pressurized to fairly high levels.
而这意味着推进剂罐必须被加压到相当高的水平
What we have on Starship is main tanks pressurized to maybe 3 or 4 atmospheres.
而星船上的主储罐可能会被加压到3或4个大气压
And the Raptor engines include their full flow stage combustion cycle,
而猛禽发动机所具有的全流量分级燃烧循环
which means pumps that raise the pressure up, maybe as high as, oh, 300 bar, right.
这意味着泵可以把压力提高到300巴 对吧
300 atmospheres in that combustion chamber.
也就是燃烧室内高达300个大气压的压力
So if you took that three atmospheres of pressure
那么 如果你把那三个大气压的压力
and use that to work a reaction control thrust or system
用来启动RCS
you would get some pretty anemic thrust, right?
推力可就太逊了 对吧
Simply, it needs more pressure.
简单来说 它需要更多的压力
So for Starship, you may have this thruster assembly already figured out,
所以对于星船 推进器组件可能已经是现成的了
but to support it,
但为了支持它
you're going to need a separate high pressure propulsion and fuel system, fuel and oxidizer tanks.
你会需要一个单独的高压推进和燃料系统 燃料和氧化剂罐
And like, for the test flights, those will probably be separate tanks,
而且 对于试飞来说 可能要使用另外的储罐
but if you imagine a Starship that's going to be flying to Mars or the moon or whatever,
但如果要使用一艘将飞往火星或月球或其他地方的星船
It's actually more likely that what they'll do is have little pumps or compressors
实际上更有可能的是 他们会使用小型的泵或者压缩机
that will take propellant from the main tanks,
来把推进剂从主储罐中取出来
and we'll pump it into these little tanks
然后泵入这些小储罐中
and then pressurize it to the relevant volume.
再加压到相应的体积
And then after they've used the RCS, they can pump some more,
接着在使用了RCS之后 可以再抽一些
and so they don't need to have these high powered pumps,
这样就不需要有这些高功率的泵
like in the engines, they can have much lower powered electric ones
就像在发动机里一样 他们可以使用更低功率的电动泵
that let them just replenish their attitude control propellant over time.
这样可以不断地补充姿态控制推进剂
So there is another thing that has been mentioned about these
那么 还有一件事 已经提到了这些事情
is that most people, I think, based on comments that Elon has dropped
是大多数人 我认为 是根据马一龙所做的评论
think that these are going to be gas-gas thrusters.
认为这些将是气-气推进器
As opposed to liquid-liquid thrusters,
而不是液-液推进器
so Morpheus, they used liquid oxygen and liquid methane,
那么墨菲斯使用的是液氧和液态甲烷
and those were fed directly into the thrusters, and they generated thrust.
会被直接送入推进器 并产生推力
But gas-gas is where you allow the stuff to vaporize before it actually reaches the combustion chambers.
但是 气-气是指在实际到达燃烧室之前就汽化了
There might be some like heat exchanger involved that, make sure it gets boiled beforehand.
可能有一些类似热交换器的东西 确保它在这之前就沸腾了
But like there's some versions of this
但是 有一些版本是这样的
where you would have separate high pressure gas tanks
你会有单独的高压气罐
containing the meth- methane and the oxygen in gaseous form.
包含气态甲烷和氧
There's a couple of advantages, first of all,
这有几个好处 首先
when you're dealing with a liquid, you have to blow it through fuel injectors,
当你处理一种液体时 必须得让其流过喷注器
which turn it into fine mist spray
使之变成细密的喷雾
that mixes very quickly, improved its combustion.
这样才能非常快地混合 促进燃烧
You lose that that adds complexity.
这增加了复杂度
If the ignition is slightly harder, and it takes a little longer to warm up and get up to speed,
如果点火稍微有点困难 就需要更长的时间来预热并达到速度
so gas-gas, on the other hand, you don't need these fancy injectors.
那么气-气 在另一方面 你不需要这些花哨的喷注器
The ignition and startup is very, very fast because it's already in gas form.
点火和启动是非常非常快的 因为它已经是气体形式
But also, if you're in zero G and you have a propellent tank
但是 如果你在零重力状态下 你有一个推进剂罐
and you try to drain a liquid off it,
而你试图把液体排出去
there's no guarantee that you're going to get liquid.
不能保证你会得到液体
You might get the gas bubbles at the top.
你可能会得到储罐顶部的气泡
But if you have a gas tank, you know you're gonna get gases,
但如果你有一个纯气体的储罐 你知道你会得到气体
so this is one set of speculation that says this is what they might be using for these.
那么这是一种猜测 也就是他们可能会使用这样的东西
Yeah there's some other ideas here, by the way,
是的 还有一些别的想法 顺便说一下
because Lunar Starship also has these other engines at the top,
因为月球版星船在顶部也有这些类似的发动机
and there's a lot of speculation that these will be pressure fed engines as well,
有很多猜测认为这些也将是挤压式发动机
just because they're trying to develop them very quickly.
只是因为他们正试图快速开发它们
They might be like scaled up version of the Kestrel engine
它们可能是红隼发动机的放大版
that was used on the second stage of the Falcon 1.
而红隼是猎鹰1号的二级发动机
Obviously, it wouldn't be using kerosene and liquid oxygen.
很明显 它不会(像之前那样)使用煤油和液氧
It will be using methlox.
而会使用液氧甲烷
So it would be Kestrel on meth.
因此 它将是甲烷版红隼发动机
These are needed
这种发动机是必要的
because they don't want to use the main Raptor engines, for landing on the moon,
因为着陆月球的时候不便用猛禽主发动机
because of the amount of regolith that would get blown about.
那样就会有大量的月壤被吹起
But it turns out, yeah, Kestrel sort of scaled engine.
但事实证明 是的 红隼的比例是差不多的
Large numbers of them
使用大量的挤压循环红隼发动机
could very easily land the several hundred ton rocket on the moon using pressure fed engines.
可以非常容易地将几百吨的火箭降落在月球上
So anyway, while development continues on Starship,
那么无论如何 在继续开发星船的同时
it is worth noting and realizing that
值得注意的是
while the vehicle look broadly similar to what we was suggested,
虽然航天器看起来与我们所了解到的大致相似
looks like it's fully functioning,
看起来能完成任务
it still has a lot of internal systems that are still being developed and tweaked, right?
但仍然有很多内部系统在开发和调整中 对吧
There's a lot of things that we can't see
有很多东西是我们看不到的
which will evolved and develop over time before we reach the final product.
在完工之前 还会发生很多变化
I'm Scott Manley. Fly safe.
我是Scott Manley 切记 注意飞行安全